# **MICHELLE ZOU**

# **UX Designer/Frontend Development**

## CONTACT

#### **PROFILE**

587.968.0998

michellezux@gmail.com https://michellezou.net linkedin.com/in/michellezux https://github.com/Michellezux/ portfolio-website UX Designer with diverse backgrounds in fine art, advertising, marketing, design, and customer service. Having years of experience doing user research, prototyping, user testing, and designing experience. Empathizing with users and understanding their needs, thoughts, emotions, and motivations. Having an interest in concept sketching, and design iteration. Looking forward to using my past working experiences and the latest UX design skills to solve design problems and to develop solutions to improve the experience of a user.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **DESIGN PROJECTS**

# **UX Design Certificate** CareerFoundry | Oct.2020

Key Coursework:
User-Centered Design

Research Methods User Personas User Journeys User Flows

Mobile-First Design Information Architecture Wireframe Prototyping Usability Testing

Visual Design CSS/HTML/JavaScript

# **UX Designer | Expertise APP**

- People have trouble finding real experts online who can help them to solve problems in their daily life. We provide users an app where they can search for verified experts in any field and communicate with them anytime.
- I used Sketch, InVision, Balsamiq tools.

## **UX Designer | Talking Parrot APP**

- Talking Parrot is a vocabulary learning app, and focused on learning new vocabulary.
- I using Marvel, Sketch, InVision tools.

# Frontend Development/UX Designer | My Portfolio Site

- To built a responsive website that will showcase my design portfolio to professional network as well as potential employers.
- I using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

# Information & Record Management Coursework

# SAIT POLYTECHNIC | 2014-2016

Key Coursework:
Information & Records Management
Professional Communications &
Presentation Skills
Business Imaging Technology
Enterprise Content Management Strategic

# Master of Advertising RMIT UNIVERSITY | 2005-2006

Key Coursework:

Records Management

Creativity in Advertising Advertising
Theory and Practice Marketing
Management and Implementation
Communication Theory & Practice
Advertising Campaigns
Advertising Strategy Planning Advertising
Media Strategy

# **EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS**

#### **RETAIL CONSULTANT | Dec. 2012-Present**

#### Freelance

- Recommend suitable health products and answer questions according to customer requirements via telephone, email, and chat.
- Contact manufacturers and retailers to answer customer questions about specific products.
- Tracking and engaging in follow-up conversations about products, as needed.
- Empathy and interaction with customers, understanding they're buying journeys, their needs, wants, and pain points.
- Document all inquiries, requests, resolutions, and follow-up tasks.

#### LECTURER | Feb. 2007-Dec. 2009

#### Xi'An Technological University, Xi'An, CHINA

- Taught undergraduate classes, including Advertising Creativity, Marketing, and Advertising English.
- Researched students' learning needs and designed curriculum.
- Developed all course materials, including paper and digital.
- Evaluated the impact of the course based on students' feedback, surveys, and analytics.

# **MICHELLE ZOU**

# **UX Designer/Frontend Development**

Innovation and Change in Advertising
Public Relations Theory & Practice
Web Software and Design
Managing Advertising: Agency and Client
Approaches

## **Bachelor of Arts**

Xi'An Academy of Fine Arts, Xi'An, Shaanxi, PR CHINA

#### **SKILLS**

User-Centered Design
User Research
Competitive Analysis
User Surveys/Interviews
Persona Creation
Journey Maps
User Flows
Sitemaps
Information Architecture
Storyboard
Wireframing
Prototyping
Usability Testing
Advertising/Marketing

#### **TOOLS**

UX/UI Design Sketch InVison Balsamiq Keynote Marvel HTML5/CSS JavaScript

#### LANGUAGES

English Mandarin Japanese

- Instructed students to participate in advertising projects in the field of market research, creativity, and strategy.
- Supervised undergraduate student's thesis.

### ACCOUNT MANAGER | Feb. 2002-Jan. 2005

SanYe Advertising Agency, Xi'An, CHINA

- Founded and managed a self-owned Advertising Agency.
- Led an 8-person team working on a range of projects for research and commercial applications in marketing, media, branding, advertising, creative, interactive communication.
- Empathized with users/clients to understand their pain points, goals, needs, and frustrations.
- Researched and developed targeted project strategy and project planning for participating in advertising bids.
- Participated in the design process and output to craft deliverables includes market research, user research, storyboard, UX strategy, visual identity, photography.
- Developed proposals, contracts, and pricing for target accounts.
- Ensured the timely and successful delivery of our solutions according to customer needs and objectives.
- Built and maintained a strong relationship with clients, design team, marketing, and accounting.

## RELEVANT PRIOR EXPERIENCE

#### **ART DESIGNER**

## Northwestern Polytechnical University Press, CHINA

- Designed over 100 books' cover, including series English storybooks, textbooks, novels, and in-house magazines.
- Researched ideas to determine the best visual design and layout.
- Met and discussed the design with the author and the editor.
- Reviewed and revised the design, contacted printing house, and manage documents.

#### **JOURNALIST**

## Xinhua News Agency, Xi'An, CHINA

- Researched and empathized with people's experiences to uncover interesting and significant news stories.
- Obtained first-hand information by being present in happenings.
- Planned and organized the large-scale donation event.
- Interviewed the key persons in the Special Report, collected and analyzed information, and wrote the report.